As Peter said, tempered
glass like in your car,
it's done with air cooling.
That's literally what
those circles are.
If you cool it even faster--
bam, faster cooling.
You now know, what does
faster cooling mean?
Well, if it's going
to form a glass
you might be all the way
near the melting point,
and you're going to have an
even-higher volume per mole
which is going to cause even
more stress within the glass
which is going to
make the surface very
strong because it's
all compressed,
but it's also going to
have a lot of energy in it
that it wants to release.
Let's see.
We were here on
Monday, and because I
was talking about other ways
to change the properties--
in fact, remember, I showed you
a couple of different examples
of glass, right, a glass
cup and a glass bottle,
and it turns out there
is not just silica in it.
There's all these
other things in it,
and there's many,
many kinds of glass.
And I listed a few here.
This was from Monday,
so I'm showing it again.
And going all the way back
to glass made in ancient Rome
you'll find that it's got
these other ingredients.
Why?
So that's what I want
to talk about next.
Well, let's use this.
So if you notice--
and this is where
we left off Monday--
if you notice something
like calcium oxide, well,
it's going to go
to Ca2+ and O2-.